Shriroop Parikh

E-mail shriroop@gmail.com Mobile +44 (0)7739572073

Profile

An enthusiastic leader with excellent communication skills and the ability to fit in quickly and effectively within any team. As a Certified ScrumMaster, I possess, a well-developed business awareness and an understanding of the working environment needed to ensure any deadlines are met and to positively promote the company.

With more than 18+ years of international experience, I am now keen to further my career in digital innovation and blockchain architecture with a particular view to enhance my working knowledge and experience in digital technologies and pre-sales consultation.

Work Experience

Jan 2018 – Till date : Technical Solutions Architecture Managing Consultant – NTT Data UK, City of London, London, UK.

- The role involves working across clients providing technology reviews, technology strategies, high level designs and design authority governance in the digital space including eCommerce, Portals, Content Management Platforms, Omni-channel and Multidevice solutions using products such as Adobe AEM, Sitecore, etc.
- Ensure that all project/product technical paths are designed appropriately and cleanly with low cost solutions that meet or exceed the business expectations and that all technical issues and risks are managed appropriately and resolved in a timely manner.
- Central technical point of contact on projects liaising with all stakeholders both technical and non-technical.
- In 2018 lead the Content Management Platforms squad of 9 within NTT Data UK.
- At Virgin Media the responsibility was for defining a digital solution roadmap that aligned with Horizon setup boxes to attain 4K TV over IP. Defining architecture and responsible for setting up a clear solution for development teams of the project.
- At Three UK, was part of the Design and Solution Assurance & Governance Team which provided the monitoring of the performance and execution of the Rebus programme's Prime System Integrator (PSI)'s operation.

Dec 2016 – Jan 2018 : Solutions Architect & Pre-Sales Consultant - Endava, City of London, London, UK.

- The role involves reviewing and defining architectures for digital clients. Primarily client facing role with pre-sales engagements, and includes providing technical leadership to teams in the UK and offshore.
- Work across clients providing high level designs and roadmaps in the digital space including CMS platforms, eCommerce, CRMs, mobile applications and digital transformations.
- Provide technical support to facilitate technical issue resolution, innovation, commercial evaluation, business benefit v/s cost and feasibility study.
- Deliver large scale online applications using Sitecore XP on cloud infrastructure (AWS, Azure and private clouds)
- Working with near-shore teams to develop systems which comply with the architecture best practices.
- Articulate key decisions with Product Owners and Programme Managers both internally and client side.
- Pre-sales client visits across UK to provide technical guidance and direction.

- Identifying and providing strategic and innovative Sitecore solutions that unlock revenue for the agency's existing clientele.
- Grow the reputation of the organisation with current clients and through industry conferences and publications.
- Identifying and participating in new business proposals and sales pitches.
- Responsible for educating, inspiring and mentoring technical team members, whilst taking a pragmatic approach to delivering creative, innovative digital solutions of all kinds.
- Responsible for architecture and development of web platforms for clients like Great Western Railway, Artemis Fund Managers, Thinkbox and Smith & Williamson Accountancy using ASP.NET 4.5 (C#), MVC 5.1, SQL Server 2012/2014, Sitecore CMS, Bitbucket, Team Development for Sitecore (TDS), Unicorn, Sitecore Habitat, Sitecore Rocks, TeamCity and Octopus Deploy.
- Working as part of a cross functional digital team including internal or external developers, designers and support teams.
- Engage with clients to provide high level digital designs in the digital space (including CMS, eCommerce, CRMs and mobile applications)

Tools used: Sitecore 7.2, 7.5, 8.0, 8.1; Team Development for Sitecore (TDS), Sitecore Rocks, JIRA, Confluence, NET Framework, C#, jQuery, JavaScript, IIS, MS Visual Studio 2013, MS SQL Server 2012, Bitbucket, Postman REST API Client, TeamCity, Octopus Deploy.

Nov 2014 - Jan 2015 : Sitecore Consultant (Contract) - Healthspan Ltd., Guernsey, UK.

- Responsible for architecture and development of their Uniquely You product range using ASP.NET 4.5 (C#), Web forms, SQL Server 2012 and Sitecore CMS (v7.2), Team Foundation Server (TFS).
- Creating and maintaining code to integrate with client's Sitecore CMS and bespoke ecommerce framework.
- Working as part of a cross functional digital team including internal or external designers and marketing teams with a focus on delivering 'best in class' digital solutions for Healthspan customers
- Suggest changes to client's existing Sitecore architecture to ensure a right balance of agile and robust Sitecore platform is maintained.

Tools used: Sitecore 7.2, JIRA, NET Framework, C#, jQuery, JavaScript, IIS, MS Visual Studio 2013, MS SQL Server 2012 & MS Team Foundation Server (TFS)

Apr 2014 - Oct 2014 : Senior Sitecore Consultant - Valtech Ltd., Barbican, London, UK.

- Lead Sitecore Best Practices on Technical Architecture & Taxonomy.
- Lead designing and implementation of complex solution in multiple technology stacks.
- Identify strategic options in line with client goals to negotiate scope, research, evaluate and select new technologies that add value to the client's business.
- Maintain relationship with Sitecore UK to build new business and cultivate relationships.
- Contribute to enterprise architecture decisions to ensure a right balance of agile and extendible architecture is implemented for clients like Schroders, Park Resorts and International SOS.
- Responsible for architecture and development of caravan parks website using ASP.NET 4.5 (C#), MVC 5.1, SQL Server 2012 and Sitecore CMS (v7.2).
- Communicate the requirements that are raised for new or changed team members to Resource Manager.

Tools used: Sitecore 7.2, TeamCity, JIRA, GitHub & Bitbucket, NET Framework, MVC, C#, jQuery, JavaScript, IIS, Razor, MS Visual Studio 2013, MS SQL Server 2012.

Apr 2009 - Apr 2014 : Sitecore Systems Consultant - Saga Group Ltd., Folkestone, Kent, UK.

- Design technical architecture for Sitecore that is robust, scalable and maintainable.
- Design, setup and manage build, production, staging, live and DR environments for Sitecore.
- Analyse business requirements and convert them into effective CMS solutions.
- Implement efficient methodologies and standards to ensure smooth internal processes.
- Define publishing strategy for various Sitecore environments.
- Implement Sitecore content validation rules for various content editors.
- Define workflows in Sitecore for various business users.
- Involve in development of Content Migration Tool from old CMS to Sitecore.
- Use concepts like MEF and NServiceBus in implementing reliable application extensions like web services and customised assemblies for Sitecore.
- Responsible for complete end-to-end capability for delivery of systems solutions to the business, including feasibility analysis, project control, design, development, migration, testing and delivery.
- Involve in delivery of business value, and within that, the ability to utilise any core, or available technology to achieve this goal.

Tools used: Sitecore 6.3 & 6.5, .NET Framework, MVC, NServiceBus, C#, ASP, VB Script, jQuery, JavaScript, IIS, HTML, XML, XSLT & XHTML, MS Visual Studio 2010, MS SQL Server 2008 & 2012, Dapper, SVN & Mercurial Hg, TeamCity and MS Build Scripts.

Jan 2007 - Feb 2009 : Technical Project Manager - Nikon Optical UK Ltd., Milton Keynes, Bucks, UK. (Position made redundant)

- Analysis, deployment and development of new projects based on the current optical industry's manufacturing requirements.
- Analysis and integration of automated robotic machines in production line with existing set up of Production Management Application.
- Customer Services Management System, which mainly maintains the tracks of products returned and replaced, reports on current lead time on product delivery based on the order placed, zero tolerance reports and reports on products need chasing in various production departments. Reports developed using C# and MS SQL Server 2005 Reporting Services.
- Improve the existing functionality of user interface and reporting tool in order to maximise the results.
- Create and implement Work In Progress module in order to monitor the real time work in progress on the production floor.
- Report to MIS Manager and Production Director.
- Liaise with the production team in the production line.

Tools used: MS Visual Studio 2005, ASP.NET, C#, ASP, VB6, VB Script, JavaScript, IIS, ADO & ADO.NET, XML & HTML using MS SQL Server 2000 and 2005.

Oct 2006 - Jan 2007 : Commerce Server Developer (Contract) - Acela Ltd., Long Buckby, Northants, UK.

- Responsible for initial development and maintenance of e-commerce websites for Maclaren, Laser Sailing and Ronson international companies that served both the consumer and business markets in Europe and North America, helping to reach new customers and improving efficiency of our sales and distribution channels.
- Work closely with Acela's strategic creative services counterpart, Dory to produce an enhanced e-commerce website in accordance with the business needs.
- Specific Functional Responsibilities:
 - Implement and configure the basic launch functionality for Commerce Server 2007.
 - Implement e-commerce solutions (B2B & B2C) for Acela's client brands for multiple global markets and in multiple languages.
 - Develop the core and site-specific functionality according to business needs and

integrate e-commerce functionality with Acela's ERP platform MS Navision.

- Provide ongoing tactical support on the maintenance, updating, and reporting from commerce server to the clients.
- Work closely with MS SharePoint for management activities

Tools used: Commerce Server 2007, Biz Talk Adaptors, MS Visual Studio 2005, ASP.NET, C#, VB Script, JavaScript, IIS, ADO.NET, Worldpay, XML & HTML using MS SQL Server 2005.

Jul 2006 - Oct 2006

: IT Software Developer (Contract) - Nikon Optical UK Ltd., Milton Keynes, Bucks, UK.

- Support and update a bespoke application (PROMA) to manage the production line.
- Improve the existing functionality of user interface and reporting tool in order to maximise the results.
- Create and implement Work In Progress module in order to monitor the real time work in progress on the production floor.
- Report to MIS Manager and liaise with the Production Team in the production

Tools used: ASP, VB Script, JavaScript, IIS, ADO, XML & HTML using MS SQL Server 2000.

Aug 2003 - April 2006 : Senior Developer - Marginz Ltd., Huntingdon, Cambridgeshire, UK.

- Involvement in project allocation and development of Marginz website.
- Report directly to Director about the progress of the projects.
- Design and develop www.efaze.com_website for Marginz Ltd for Online Company Formation at Companies House.
- Liaise with developers for database design and configuration of web server. Tools used: ASP, JavaScript, MS Visual Basic, MTS, VBA ADO, DCOM/COM+, Worldpay, Crystal Reports 7.0, XML & HTML using the databases MS Access and MS SQL Server.

Apr 2003 - Aug 2003

: Software Consultant (Contract) - University Of Hertfordshire, Hatfield, Hertfordshire, UK.

- Design and develop Project Management Software for the University of Hertfordshire.
- Deliver complete automation software to the Department of Design, Technology and Management.

Tools used: MS Visual Basic, VBA, MS Project, MS Access and MS SQL.

Academic Qualifications

Sep 2001 - Sep 2002

: MSc Computer Science, University of Hertfordshire, Hatfield, UK Selected as a National Students Learning Program (NSLP) Training Instructor by the University of Hertfordshire Students Union.

Attended National Union of Students' (NUS) Learning Programme on Running Meetings, Negotiation, Communication, Presentation and Assertiveness.

Jun 1996 - May 1999

: BSc (Special) Electronics, Gujarat University, Ahmedabad, India.

Achieved several awards for academic excellence.

Professional Qualifications

Certification Courses: Blockchain Advanced Level: Uses Beyond Bitcoin,

Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure,

SAFe® 4 Product Owner/Product Manager Course (preparing for certification),

Certified ScrumMaster,

.NET 2.0 Programming with C# & VB.NET, Microsoft Solution Developer (MCSD).

Sitecore Certifications: Sitecore DMS .NET Developer (DND),

Website .NET Developer Certification for Sitecore,

CMS 6.5 (SND) and Developer Foundations for Sitecore CMS 6.2 (SDF)

Computer Skills

CMS : Sitecore 6.3, 6.5, 7.2, 7.5, 8.0, 8.1, 8.2 and Umbraco 7. **Source Control** : SVN, BitBucket, GitHub and Team Foundation Server (TFS).

IDEs : MS Visual Studio 2010, 2012 & 2013.

Web Languages : XML, XHTML, ASP, ASP.NET, JavaScript, jQuery, VBScript, DHTML & HTML

Languages : C, C++ and C#.

Database : MS SQL Server, Oracle and MS Access.

Front-End : MS Visual Basic and VB.NET.

Interests and Activities

Reading books and articles, particularly on FinTech, Finance Management and Agile Business Management.

• Playing Table Tennis and Badminton. Enjoy watching Cricket, Formula 1 and Tennis.

References will be available on request.